<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-25T16:30:49+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">UNSW Casuals Network</title><subtitle>The UNSW Casuals Network is a grassroots organisation of casualised and insecure staff at UNSW, fighting for job security and better working conditions.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Unsw Casuals Response To Conversion Emails</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/25/UNSW-Casuals-Response-To-Conversion-Emails.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unsw Casuals Response To Conversion Emails" /><published>2021-10-25T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2021-10-25T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/25/UNSW-Casuals-Response-To-Conversion-Emails</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/25/UNSW-Casuals-Response-To-Conversion-Emails.html">&lt;p&gt;THERE’S NOTHING ‘CASUAL’ ABOUT BEING PRECARIOUSLY EMPLOYED AT UNSW: STOP CASUALISATION AND UNFAIR WORK PRACTICES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve just released our open letter in response to the recent emails about casual conversion. We demand to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What process, if any, was undertaken to assess casuals on an individual basis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who undertook the assessments and how they were qualified to do so&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many casuals were affected, and of those, how many were made offers for conversion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why research-active casuals were not recognised&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why casual academic staff were not evaluated against criteria for education focused roles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/RSQM3MY3pJvFuPkm6&quot;&gt;Sign Here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">THERE’S NOTHING ‘CASUAL’ ABOUT BEING PRECARIOUSLY EMPLOYED AT UNSW: STOP CASUALISATION AND UNFAIR WORK PRACTICES</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UNSW Class Sizes Report and Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/21/Class-Sizes-Report.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UNSW Class Sizes Report and Website" /><published>2020-09-21T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-09-21T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/21/Class-Sizes-Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/21/Class-Sizes-Report.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/15J7hL__-Twgy9aprSTP9HxuylRNw6ixj/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/report-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of the Class Sizes report cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/15J7hL__-Twgy9aprSTP9HxuylRNw6ixj/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; released today by the UNSW Casuals Network shows that class sizes have increased significantly over the past year, with tutorial sizes increasing by an average of 13.8% across the university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report analyses data on class enrolments from 2016 to 2020, and highlights particular increases in large first-year courses in areas such as mathematics, chemistry, arts and design. Quotes from students in the report testify to how difficult it is for them to learn in these conditions: they describe huge online classes as “uncomfortable”, “impersonal”, and “a huge waste of time”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report is accompanied by an &lt;a href=&quot;https://classes.unswcasuals.net/&quot;&gt;interactive website&lt;/a&gt; which allows users to search for subject and course codes and see the change in class sizes over recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://classes.unswcasuals.net/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/class-size-search.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of the UNSW Class Size Search website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest increases in class sizes have come in 2020, as UNSW and other universities slash budgets during the COVID-19 pandemic. Many casualised teaching staff have &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/more-than-70-of-academics-at-some-universities-are-casuals-theyre-losing-work-and-are-cut-out-of-jobkeeper-137778&quot;&gt;lost work&lt;/a&gt;, and almost 500 ongoing staff members at UNSW are now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-07-15/almost-500-jobs-cut-at-unsw-due-to-coronavirus-impact/12459228&quot;&gt;facing redundancies&lt;/a&gt;. As more staff are fired, student-to-staff ratios will further decrease, weakening UNSW’s existing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smh.com.au/education/the-australian-universities-among-the-world-s-top-50-20190618-p51yuo.html&quot;&gt;low rankings&lt;/a&gt; on this measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University teaching work is overwhelmingly carried out by casualised workers, for whom bigger classes mean bigger workloads with no extra pay - in other words, more unpaid hours. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-08-05/university-of-melbourne-exposed-in-decade-long-wage-theft-case/12519588&quot;&gt;investigations into wage theft&lt;/a&gt; continue at a number of Australian universities, including UNSW, swelling class sizes must be addressed as a key issue driving unpaid work for casualised teaching staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This report builds on an earlier report that we released in April 2020 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unswcasuals.net/2020/04/28/UNSW-Casuals-Survey-Report.html&quot;&gt;Under the Pump, Unpaid and Uncertain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; which documented the early impacts of COVID-19 on casualised staff at UNSW. The inquiry found high levels of anxiety and fear regarding job security and widespread wage theft, with many casual staff working more than 10 unpaid hours each week.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UNSW Casuals Network statement against transphobia within the NTEU</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/25/Statement-against-transphobia-within-the-NTEU.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UNSW Casuals Network statement against transphobia within the NTEU" /><published>2020-08-25T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-25T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/25/Statement-against-transphobia-within-the-NTEU</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/25/Statement-against-transphobia-within-the-NTEU.html">&lt;p&gt;The most recent meeting of the UNSW Casuals Network unanimously passed the following statement against transphobia within the NTEU:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This meeting of the UNSW Casuals Network stands in solidarity with LGBTQI+ communities. It is our responsibility to call out transphobic, homophobic, sexist and other exclusionary behaviour in our activist spaces. We condemn the transphobic statements of Virginia Mansel-Lees, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1ds1KuZOCzutSVhTRBfRxfVM8JV7BUc7Py135qAFrYWY/&quot;&gt;endorse the following open letter&lt;/a&gt; calling for Virginia’s removal as Convener of the NTEU’s Queer Unionists in Tertiary Education (QUTE) network. We will also email this motion to the NTEU National, NSW, Victorian and UNSW branch presidents. Transgender rights are union business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The most recent meeting of the UNSW Casuals Network unanimously passed the following statement against transphobia within the NTEU:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Statement on the UNSW Restructure</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/Statement-on-the-UNSW-Restructure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Statement on the UNSW Restructure" /><published>2020-07-24T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-07-24T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/Statement-on-the-UNSW-Restructure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/Statement-on-the-UNSW-Restructure.html">&lt;p&gt;The UNSW Casuals Network rejects the rationale offered to us by the university for its proposed restructures and job cuts. Instead of supporting students and workers in our struggle against government defunding, UNSW leadership are choosing once again to impose the costs of uncertainty on those who are least able to bear it. We speak here particularly of those students and workers — academic, professional, or otherwise — whose limited options in this moment are the product of decades worth of ‘economic rationalism’ and centuries worth of slavery and colonisation. These measures are not necessary. They are a function of power and domination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The university leadership’s appeal to a mission of ‘social impact’ is designed to whitewash its callous profit-seeking behaviour, which discards and demoralises in order to enrich a small group of senior leaders, with our millionaire VC at the top. Their actions do not support communities of students and workers but instead create an atmosphere of fear and uncertainty. The recent actions of the university’s senior leadership make it clear that their supposed ‘social commitment’ is little more than a self-interested performance. Students and workers — many of whom have struggled hard against genocide, borders, poverty, and sexism — mean nothing to them if we cannot generate profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The university has made no effort to demonstrate that it is acting in good-faith. Surveys were administered to solicit feedback from staff — but, as no plan for recovery from COVID-19 was provided, staff were rightly confused about what they were being asked to provide feedback on. All communications with students and staff have either been one-way or via meaningless and highly stage-managed Q&amp;amp;A sessions. Our union has been stonewalled, and staff and students have no independent access to the university’s financial data. Decisions about how financial reserves are being used have been shrouded in a smokescreen of obfuscation. School managers are already being asked to identify areas where cuts ought to be made, making a mockery of our VC’s supposed commitment to transparency and further demonstrating that the university has no real interest in public and deliberative decision making. In short, we are being pushed through a fake consultation process that we have been given no agency over other than to comply or resign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The university’s ‘consultation’ process has been a masterclass in managerialism. The Taskforce 20/21+ analysis of areas in which teaching and research can be ‘optimised’ is remarkably thin, suggesting a weak academic and pedagogical rationale behind the proposed faculty mergers. Yet, these studies apparently inform one of the most substantial restructures in the university’s history, which will result in the removal of 493 FTE positions. The loss of these staff, coupled with the abandonment of casualised and fixed term workers whose contracts have not been renewed, will have extensive negative effects on teaching and research in both the short and long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cuts to professional staff that come with centralisation will be felt most keenly. Their dismissal will exacerbate an already poor work and study experience (UNSW was ranked last in Australia in the 2019 Student Experience Survey). Remaining staff will be forced to take on even greater workload, and pressure will increase to ignore the poor treatment and unpaid hours experienced by casualised workers. The emphasis on ‘flexibility’ is simply a euphemism for more insecure employment and the further transfer of power and control towards university management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UNSW Casuals Network refuses the cynical, exclusionary, and exploitative terms upon which this miserable restructure rests. We are committed to working with students and workers across and beyond our university to call our management into a process that is accountable to the people whom the university cannot function without. We are prepared to demonstrate forms of social and ethical commitment that the university’s management can only pretend to value. We will work as hard as we can to connect and coordinate across faculties, industries, and borders to change the terms of this discussion in favour of those with the most at stake in the running of this institution. If you would like to be a part of this process, please get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UNSW Casuals Network&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The UNSW Casuals Network rejects the rationale offered to us by the university for its proposed restructures and job cuts. Instead of supporting students and workers in our struggle against government defunding, UNSW leadership are choosing once again to impose the costs of uncertainty on those who are least able to bear it. We speak here particularly of those students and workers — academic, professional, or otherwise — whose limited options in this moment are the product of decades worth of ‘economic rationalism’ and centuries worth of slavery and colonisation. These measures are not necessary. They are a function of power and domination.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our Networks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/30/Our-Networks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our Networks" /><published>2020-06-30T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-06-30T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/30/Our-Networks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/30/Our-Networks.html">&lt;p&gt;Members of the UNSW Casuals Network are also involved in organising in other groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a great guide to the current state of organising groups in Australia, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/uniworkersupport.australia/permalink/1565985330231664/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; (you’ll need to join the COVID-19 Uni Workers Support Facebook Group).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are members of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nteu.org.au/&quot;&gt;NTEU&lt;/a&gt; - National Tertiary Education Union&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/NHEActionNetwork/?ref=br_rs&quot;&gt;NHEAN&lt;/a&gt; - National Higher Education Action Network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/NHECN/?ref=br_rs&quot;&gt;NHECN&lt;/a&gt; - National Higher Education Casuals Network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/StudentFightback/&quot;&gt;Student Fightback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Members of the UNSW Casuals Network are also involved in organising in other groups.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UNSW Education Collective</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/UNSW-Education-Collective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UNSW Education Collective" /><published>2020-05-20T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/UNSW-Education-Collective</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/UNSW-Education-Collective.html">&lt;p&gt;So great to have the support of student unionists! ✊ Attacks on staff working conditions are attacks on students’ learning conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“University students have a proud history of supporting NTEU strikes in the past and we’re willing to fight alongside staff who reject the idea that they should sacrifice pay and conditions for the university’s profits. Instead of putting the cost of this crisis onto staff and students, universities should dip into their enormous cash reserves and investment portfolio assets to fund their revenue shortfalls, and the government should fully fund free public higher education.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook link &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/UNSWedcollective/?__xts__[0]=68.ARAzg-iBS5I2yR8X88-GudQ9RFnyDtzoZTRLV6-vhvsTaj74818x_xLWqXPUwm_yoCS2CdczQZQraKGyVPf0qKQrGk5I46VZRfexcZ8brsTrFtMZ3P3P5yfFTP_N1ymA15hoaM0NU7q6Es3rImdJxqt_5KGa-e28FDKRJDeTZivaZxdhTj7fjL6BNG0mubevH-zo5uWglN-dXi1LkLSuJb0mwLFUHAZ7vcirgSv3T_jU2JhG5_F6WrMlgQKerdtZ-tWYrO_iDDAvMkDAVShDwlbw5ILwAgc9Eu7ttJ-troc94aXS0WrDRWH8PYVf9XcKniMdOtBMHNpIJjHuwVgcq_fbvzegoWK9n9pGGM73Vj-L7QRHpkhR5iT6FZ1uhepVeIje_CL2DZfE14Yb9UQ9AWVMhjx9zfI7AJujNVnuHJpiMWVJ5CbOqE3Ic-TrTgqi0bfHVMJVFw_mKCZAkU5Ga7lr2s3DIJJIYM6VYgvpOmqVXhumVF7O&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So great to have the support of student unionists! ✊ Attacks on staff working conditions are attacks on students’ learning conditions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Petition to UNSW management</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/08/Petition-to-UNSW-management.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Petition to UNSW management" /><published>2020-05-08T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-05-08T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/08/Petition-to-UNSW-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/08/Petition-to-UNSW-management.html">&lt;p&gt;The UNSW Casuals Network has created a petition for all UNSW staff to show solidarity with precarious workers. It attempts to outline some of the situation with how precarious workers are becoming the first victims of COVID-19 cost-cutting, the value of these workers to the education system, the potential impact to student learning, and the importance of secure staff not taking voluntary concessions. Please sign and share if you would like to show solidarity with this cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/jjANHf2Hin5KnYz9A&quot;&gt;Petition Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The UNSW Casuals Network has created a petition for all UNSW staff to show solidarity with precarious workers. It attempts to outline some of the situation with how precarious workers are becoming the first victims of COVID-19 cost-cutting, the value of these workers to the education system, the potential impact to student learning, and the importance of secure staff not taking voluntary concessions. Please sign and share if you would like to show solidarity with this cause.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UNSW Casuals Survey Report</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/28/UNSW-Casuals-Survey-Report.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UNSW Casuals Survey Report" /><published>2020-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/28/UNSW-Casuals-Survey-Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/28/UNSW-Casuals-Survey-Report.html">&lt;p&gt;Last week we released the results of a survey conducted in April of casual staff at UNSW. The report includes some staggering but unsurprising findings: casuals are already the prime collateral as UNSW seeks to restructure work at the university in order to cut costs. We found that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;1 in 3 UNSW casual workers had already lost work as a result of COVID-19&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;81% fear that they will lose their job this year&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;41% are currently working unpaid hours, with one in three of these working more than 10 hours unpaid per week&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey shows that if we don’t assert our interests now, most of us won’t have jobs at UNSW next term. Join the UNSW Casuals Network now to fight back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full report &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1aiXDTewJF9f1-PRKtvnpBmSAw4qW2kMR/view&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last week we released the results of a survey conducted in April of casual staff at UNSW. The report includes some staggering but unsurprising findings: casuals are already the prime collateral as UNSW seeks to restructure work at the university in order to cut costs. We found that:</summary></entry></feed>